本字幕由 YYeTs人人影視 翻譯創作
歡迎愛好者加入我們  www.YYeTs.com
■
翻譯：spriteNT   小豬兒想媽媽   鬼瞳1540  時間軸：End
校對：小砂鍋 監製：可樂嘻嘻  後期：yyp
■
源代碼
我採納了你的意見  很不錯  謝了
I took your advice. It was good advice,thank you.
你臉色蒼白  沒事吧
You're pale,everything ok?
肖恩
Shawn.
Shawn!
聽著  我之所以要取消...
Anyway listen I wanted to tell you,only reason why I canceled...
一天給我打三次電話  現在這來電的次數
Oh,he's calling me three times a day. I hear more from him now,
比我們分手前還多  這人有毛病吧
than I did when we were together. What is it with guys?
我提出申請了
I gave notice.
您的車票
Ticket.
什麼申請
Notice?
請出示您的車票
May I see your ticket?
我...
I...
今天早上你都有點魂不守舍  沒事吧
You are acting a little strange this morning,are you ok?
您的票
Ticket?
-晚點的十分鐘能追回來吧  -先生  我們盡量
- Are we gonna make up the ten minute? - We gonna try,Sir.
老頭  他媽的怎麼晚點了
Hey,grandpa,what the hell was the delay back there?
-我只負責查票  -你真該插自己...
- I just punch the tickets,Sir. - You should punch your face...
肖恩  我做了什麼嗎
Shawn,did I do something?
聽著  我知道
Look,I can see that you
你覺得你認識我  但我不認識你
think you know me but I don't know who you are
我是考爾特·斯蒂文斯上尉
My name is Captain Colter Stevens.
我是駐阿富汗美軍的直升機飛行員
I fly helicopter for the US Army in Afghanistan.
-肖恩  這也太...  -肖恩
- Shawn,that's... - Shawn?
我有點噁心
I feel sick.
-我靠  -對不起  我幫你撿
- Dammit! - Sorry! Let me help with that...
沒事  不要緊的
No,it's ok.
沃爾特·裏德  部隊醫療中心
先生  等下
Hey mister! Hey!
-你把這落下了  -謝謝
- Hey,you dropped this! - Thanks!
-這是哪  -芝加哥
- What is that? - Chicago.
車門即將關閉  請全員上車
All aboard. Doors are closing.
本車是芝加哥城郊往返列
This is a Chicago-down train.
你沒事吧  上尉先生
You ok there,Captain?
你看到了嗎
Did you see that?
你真把我嚇到了
You kinda freaking me out.
不不不不不不不...
Oh,no,no,no,no,no,no...
西恩·芬特雷斯  教師
-你沒事吧  -我不知道到底怎麼回事
- Are you alright? - I don't know,what's going on...
-肖恩  跟我說說  -聽著  我不知道誰是肖恩
- Talk to me Shawn! - Look,I don't know who Shawn is,
我也不認識你
and I don't know who you are!
這樣  我們下站下車
Ok,we get off at the next stop
就當什麼也沒發生過  好嗎
and forget whatever is going on here,ok?
這壓根不是我的
This doesn't belong to me.
看著我  一切都會好起來的
Look at me,everything is gonna be ok!
考爾特·斯蒂文斯上尉  這是圍城
Captain Colter Stevens,this is Beleaguered Castle.
考爾特·斯蒂文斯上尉
Captain Colter Stevens,
這是圍城  請確認通信
this is Beleaguered Castle,acknowledge transmission.
斯蒂文斯上尉  收到了嗎
Captain Stevens,do you copy?
我這是在哪
Where am I?
你正在"圍城"中  你還好嗎
You are with "Beleaguered Castle." Are you functional?
頭暈  我是不是被鎖住了
I am dizzy. Did I... Did I just a-lock?
現在調整你的朝向
Adjusting your rotation.
你這次能報告了嗎
Can you report this time?
這他媽是什麼鬼東西
Fuck is this? What this is?
你在...我這是跟誰在說話
Where... who I am talking to?
上尉  描述下你剛才的所見所聞
Captain report what you saw.
我聽不懂你在說什麼
What,I don't understand it.
和我說話前  你在哪
Where were you before you were talking to me?
-那裏發生了爆炸  -哪裏
- There was an explosion. - Coming from where?
在這個階段意識有點模糊很正常  上尉
Some confusion is perfectly normal at this stage,Captain.
能看到畫面嗎
Do you have a visual signal?
你是誰
Who are you?
-你知道我是誰  -知道嗎
- You already have that information,Captain. - I do?
說出我的名字
Recall my name.
我們將重建片段  請集中注意力
We'll rebuild the pattern. Try to focus.
我...在執行任務
I... was on a mission.
在開飛機
I was flying...
醒來之後就在一輛火車上
And then I woke up on a train.
現在又到這了
Now I am here.
你得跟我說清楚
I need to be briefed.
你說這是什麼部隊來著
Uhm,wha-what unit is this?
-圍城  -誰
- You're with Beleaguered Castle. - Who?
準備啟動阿爾法記憶片段一號線程
Stand by for thread 1 of alpha memory pattern.
"圍城"是什麼
What is "Beleaguered castle?"
這些題目將對你有所幫助
The exercises will assist you.
一號記憶線程  請聽下面的段落
Memory thread 1. Listen to the following passage.
莉莉醒來時穿著晚禮服  披著夜禮服斗蓬
Lilly awoke in an evening dress and an opera cloak…
她手中拿著五張牌
...in her hand were 5 play cards.
你在講笑話嗎
Is this a joke?
黑桃Q  梅花四
The Queen of Spades,Four of Clubs...
梅花九  紅桃三  紅桃九
…Nine of Clubs,Three of Hearts,Nine of Hearts.
這是紅旗軍事訓練嗎[內利斯空軍基地的訓練]
Is this a red flag exercise?
一號線程終了  開始二號線程
End of thread 1. Thread 2:
下面是鳴角鴞的叫聲記錄
The following is a recording of a western screech-owl.
二號線程終了  片段完畢  請確認
End of thread 2. End of pattern. Acknowledge.
確認片段終了
Acknowledge end of pattern.
準備好進入片段回想了嗎
Stand by to initiate pattern recall?
啟動片段回想
Go for pattern recall.
不考慮牌色
Arrange the 5 playing cards
降序重新排列這五張牌
in order of descending value irrespective of the suit.
-Q  兩張九  四和三  -回答正確
- Queen,two nines,four and a three - That is correct.
我讀的段落
The passage I read contained
提到一個女人的名字  她叫什麼
mention of a woman's name. What was that name?
莉莉
Her name is Lilly.
正確  說出我的名字
That's correct. Recall my name.
戈德溫  你叫戈德溫
Goodwin,your name is Goodwin...
正確  上尉  歡迎回來
That is correct. Welcome back,Captain.
女士  我要和我父親說話
Ma'm,I need to talk to my father.
有人得知我回到美國了嗎
Has anybody been notified that I am stateside?
上尉  列車是誰炸的
Who bombed the train,Captain?
-什麼  -列車是誰炸的
- What? - Who bombed the train?
那個一直叫我"肖恩"的女人.
A woman kept calling me "Shawn".
那只是場邂逅  好好回想  上尉
That is incidental. Think Captain,remember back.
列車是誰炸的
Who bombed the train?
我他媽怎麼知道是誰炸了那列車
I don't know who bombed the god damned train.
-那就回去再試一次  -回哪去
- Then go back and try again. - Back where?
和上次一樣  你有八分鐘
You will have 8 minutes,same as last time.
不  我受夠這狗血的模擬測試了
No,no,no,no,no. No more bullshit sim tests,ok?
我得知道  我到底在哪
I need to know,where I am,
我的隊友又在哪  他們還好嗎
what is the location and condition of my crew.
有人知道我回國了嗎
Does anybody know that I am stateside?
你有義務告訴我這些信息
You are obligated to give me this information!
先從炸彈入手
Start with the bomb!
找出它的位置以及外觀
Where is it,what does it look like.
-確認它的類型和引爆方式  -得  得
- What kind of explosive,how is it detonated. - Right,right...
先找到炸彈  然後便能鎖定安置它的人
Find the bomb and you'll find the bomber.
找到炸彈  等下  不
Find the bomb...Wait nooo!
我採納了你的意見  很不錯  謝了
I took your advice. It was good advice. Thank you.
還行吧
Yeah,it』s good.
我選上了NALSAR的課  接下來嘛
And I signed for a NALSAR course. Next thing you know,
NALSAR法律研究的全國學院和法律研究大學
我將移居印度  尋找自我
I'll be moving to India to find myself.
-你還別說  -認識什麼不錯的大師嗎
- Don』t say... - Know any good Gurus?
她弄濕了你的鞋
Oh,she got your shoe...
你覺得呢  我算步入正軌了嗎
So,what do you think? Am I on the right track?
是同一輛火車  但又有些不同
It's the same train but it's different.
深刻啊  我也希望它與眾不同  跟你想的一樣
Deep. I hope it's different. I feel the same way.
怎麼了
What?
布萊恩打來的  他有毛病啊
Brian... What is it with guys,
把一切留給回憶不是更好嗎
everything is more beautiful in retrospect.
看起來如此真實
This looks so real.
我覺得  自己要想過得好
You know,I think it's gonna be really
就得盡可能遠離他
good for me to get as far away from him as possible.
-這細節刻畫地真贊 -您的車票
- Unbelievable detail. - Ticket.
請出示您的車票
May I see your ticket?
謝謝
Thanks.
他們不會讓行動干係人出現在我面前
They wouldn't put the doer in front of me.
行動干係人
The doer?
你很漂亮  你就是那個分心點
You are the pretty girl. The distraction.
-"分心點"  -每次模擬中都有分心點
- "Distraction"? - Every sim has one.
-晚點的十分鐘能追回來吧  -先生  我們盡量
- Are we gonna make up the ten minute? - We gonna try,Sir.
- 你是在說布萊恩的事嗎  -老頭
- Are you talking about Brian? - Hey Grandpa…
他媽的怎麼晚點了
What the hell was the delay back there?
-你在趕什麼  -什麼
- What you late for? - What?
你好像很在意時間  你在趕什麼
You seem concerned about the time. What are you late for?
我要趕一個操蛋慶典  你多管什麼閒事
I'm late to an asshole festival... I hear you're headlining.
搞笑吧  以為你誰啊  笑星啊
Oh that』s funny. Who are you,a comedian?
沒錯  他就是個喜劇演員
Yeah,he is a... comedian.
坐下  怪胎
Sit down,freak.
可怕的粉絲
Fans...
他你都不認識嗎
That』s the guy. He came in 3rd
美國達人上得了第三  兩次因為酒駕入獄
on America's Got Talent. Got sided twice for DUI.
-我們八卦過他了  -懂了  小姐  謝謝
- We talked about him. - Thank you,ma'm,thank you.
-不客氣  -格倫布魯克站到了
- You are welcome. - "Glenbrook station."
但是一點鐘那會兒橋會很堵
Yeah,but at 1 o'clock the bridge is gonna be jammed.
我靠
Damn it!
對不起
Ah,I am sorry.
親愛的  真有趣
It's funny,honey.
駕照  伊利諾
先生等下  等下
Hey Mr.! Hey!
-你把這落下了  -謝謝
- You dropped this. - Thanks.
車門即將關閉  請全員上車
All aboard,doors are closing.
本車是芝加哥城郊往返列
This is a Chicago-down train.
爆炸是在我後面來的
The explosion came from behind me.
-你是怎麼回事  -我現在沒空和你聊天
- What's with you? - Out of time to talk to you right now.
我有的是時間
I got time for you.
下一站  終點站芝加哥
The next stop,Chicago,Union Station.
我操
Oh,shit!
戈德溫  你會告訴我怎麼拆了它嗎
Goodwin,you gonna tell me how to disarm this?
我該...拆了它  還是該忽略它
Should I... unplug it? Or do you want me to just leave it?
那我不管了
I am just gonna leave it.
可以嗎
Ok?
身份證  西恩·芬特雷斯  教師
乘客們  我是運輸安全人員
Ladies and Gentleman,Transit Security.
-是個毛  -由於某項未公開的侵害安全行為
- You're not. - Due to a classified security-breach I need all of
請在進站前
you turn off your personal electronic devices
關閉所有電子設備  好嗎
till we pull into the station,ok?
手提  手機統統關閉  請關掉手機  先生
That means laptops,cell phones,cell phone,Sir.
關掉手機  先生  非常感謝
Cell phone,Sir! Thank your very much.
呼機也得關  關掉一切電子產品  謝謝
Pagers,anything electronic. Thank you.
這只是防範措施  無須擔心
It's a precautionary measure,it's nothing to worry about.
到底是什麼  有安全侵害還是防患於未然
So which is it,security breach or precautionary measure?
先生  關掉
Sir!
先生  你沒聽明白嗎
Is there a problem here,Sir?
這個重要的談判才到一半
I am in the middle of a very big deal...
肖恩
Shawn?
把那個關掉
I need you to turn that off.
把你的證件再給我瞅眼
Why you don't show me that ID again?
肖恩
Shawn!
關掉
Turn it off!
你有毛病啊  混蛋
What's your problem,asshole?
肖恩  你搞什麼鬼
Shawn,what are you doing?
女士  那麼做可不妥
Hey,not a good idea m'am.
最好別  最好別打電話哦
Not a good idea. Oh,that's not a good idea.
你把他下巴打斷了
I think you broke his jaw.
無妨  他跟你一樣  全是幻象
It's ok,he is not any more real than you are.
幻象  你下次自己開車上班去啊
I am not real? How about next time you drive to work!
沒有下次了
There's not gonna be a next time.
穩住
Stabilize.
放慢心跳
Lower your pulse.
-你找到炸彈了嗎  -是的
- Did you find the bomb? - Yes...
地上都是液壓油
There is hydraulic fluid all over the floor.
無須擔心  上尉
It's not a concern,Captain.
-這是  -跟我說說炸彈
- What is... -Tell me about the bomb.
他是誰  在監控裏拄根枴杖的男人
Where is that man? I saw a guy with a crutch on the monitor.
貌似他才是老大
He looks like he is in charge,
-我要和他談談  -那不可能  上尉
- I wanna talk to him. - That's irrelevant,Captain.
我要跟你的指揮官談談
I wanna talk to your commanding officer!
你可以在完成任務之後與他交談
You can talk to him upon completion of your mission.
我的分隊在阿富汗  我在那執行任務
My mission is in Afghanistan,where my unit is.
我他媽昨天飛了兩次
I flew two god damn sorties yesterday.
你這兩個月都跟我們在一起
You've been with us for 2 months.
-找到設彈人了嗎  -沒  我的分隊在哪裏
- Did you id the bomber? - No,where is my unit?
這個模擬實驗是誰負責的
And under whose jurisdiction is this simulation?
上尉  這不是模擬實驗
Captain,this is not a simulation.
你肩負了無數人的性命
Lives are depending on you.
什麼性命
What lives?
關於炸彈  你還記得什麼  描述一下引爆器
What do you remember about the bomb? Tell me about the detonator.
等下  什麼性命  你在說什麼
No,no,no,what lives? What you are talking about?
你得跟我說清楚
I need to be briefed!
-長官  得告訴他點內情  -沒事  說吧
- Sir,I need to give him something. - That's fine,go ahead.
準備把他送回去
Get ready to send him back in.
今早  中央標準時間七點四十八分
48 this morning CST,a bomb exploded on a
在芝加哥一輛市郊往返列車上
commuter train outside of Chicago,
一枚炸彈爆炸  無人生還
killing everyone on board.
也就是你所在的那輛列車
And that』s the train that you've been on.
不可能  我不在這嗎  你正在跟我說話
No,no,no,I am right here,you are talking to me right now!
一名叫肖恩·芬特雷斯的男人在那趟列車上
A man named Shawn Fentress was on that train.
總而言之  他現在就是你了
He,for all intents and purposes,is now you.
每多花一秒鐘解釋
Every second spent explaining
就會有更多無辜人的性命陷入危險
things puts more innocent civilians at risk.
胡說八道
This makes no sense.
火車爆炸只是一系列襲擊的第一波
The train explosion was the first attack of a series.
接下來會有更多
There are going to be more.
你找到炸彈了嗎
Now,did you find the bomb?
在廁所裏  水槽上方的通風板那
In the restroom,ventilation panel above the sink.
引爆器是手機  行了嗎
Cell phone detonator. Are we done?
還沒  不過你幹得很不錯  上尉  做得好
Eh,no no. But that's good,that's very very good,Captain. Good.
數據顯示  爆炸時刻
Our record show that 1812
共有1812通電話完成通話
calls ended at the moment of the explosion.
有五十二通電話經由離火車最近的
52 of those calls were tethered to the cell tower
信號塔轉接  其中就有設彈人打的電話
nearest the train. So one of those calls was made by our bomber.
你記不記得爆炸時
Do you remember a freight
正好有輛貨運列車經過
train passing by just before the explosion?
記得
Yes.
在爆炸發生的時刻  貨車剛好經過
The explosion was timed to engulf the passing freight train
這表明
which means,
設彈人是在可見兩車的情況下打的電話
the bomber had to be watching both trains when the call was made.
五十二個人  其中一個是設彈人
52 callers,one of those is our bomber.
我要你留意同車廂的乘客
I want you to concentrate on the passengers in your car.
瞭解他們  縮小嫌疑人範圍
Get to know them,narrow the suspect pool.
留意那些不動聲響或孤僻的傢伙
Look for ones who seem quiet or withdrawn,
和面露不安的人
who seem nervous.
同樣  你只有八分鐘
As always,you'll have 8 minutes.
八分鐘  然後我又被炸飛
8 minutes,and I blow up again?
是的
Yes.
我要你這次嚴於律己
I need you to discipline yourself on this next pass.
執行我們指定你做的任務
Perform only the task that we assign you.
其它的都無關緊要
Everything else is irrelevant.
驅動通電
Charge the drivers.
我爸爸...
Is my father even...
我採納了你的意見  很不錯
I took your advice... It was very good advice.
-你今天挺沉默的啊  -煩心事比較多  小心
- You're kinda quiet today. - Just got a lot on my mind. Careful.
-對不起啊  -沒事
- Oh,so sorry - Don't worry about it.
你真善良
That's very kind of you.
知書達理
You're very decent.
多謝誇獎
Thank you.
-也很真實  -您的車票
- And real. - Ticket.
-今天還好嗎  -不錯
- How's everything today? - It's good.
-有沒有什麼異常 -沒有
- Anything out of the ordinary? - Uhmm no.
我是指  車上人的行為
I mean behavior on the train.
有沒有...在你看來很詭異的人
Is anything... Anybody seems strange to you?
你就很詭異
You look strange.
你呢  有沒有覺得誰比較可疑
How about you,does anybody looks suspicious?
-你是喝醉了還是怎麼  -過來  就一會
- Are you drunk or something? - Come here. For a second.
來吧
Come on.
-把它當成一個遊戲  -遊戲
- Just think of it as a game. - A game?
他們再正常不過了
They are all so utterly normal,
肖恩  這也是他們的可怕之處
Shawn. That's what so terrifying about them.
也許他們暗中是一夥的
Maybe there's a team network.
睡覺的胖子和牧師還有那幾人有勾搭
The sleeping giant coached with the minister and them out there.
別忽略掉這個憂鬱的大學生  他可是犧牲品
Don't forget the sullen college kid,he is the expendable one.
我打賭  所有人都聽命於售票員
I bet they are all controlled by the conductor.
他就站在那裏專橫地查看車票
Standing there dictatorial demanding tickets.
-你太搞了  -該死的
- You are funny. - Damn it.
-那他呢  -失業中
- What about that guy? - Deposition.
他對面的那女人呢
About that woman sitting across from him?
每週一  她都會去做頭髮  你不知道嗎
Hair appointment,every Monday,you know this.
你跟他們比我跟他們聊的多啊
You talk to this people more than I do.
沒錯  她後面那男的呢
Right,right. And the guy behind her?
他試鏡要遲到了  對吧
He's late for an audition,right?
他可有犯罪記錄  被送進過...
To record offenses... That's the guy that was sided...
酒後駕車  我懂  信號咋樣
A DUI,I know. Hey,how』s the signal in here?
不錯
It's good.
平時教書還不夠刺激嗎  大偵探
Is teaching not stimulating enough for you anymore,Sherlock?
看來我們又遇到種族問題了
Oh oh,now we slip to the racial profiling,that is.
還有別人從廁所出來過嗎
Did anyone else come out of the bathroom over there?
-我看到你從裏面出來  -我
- Well,I saw you coming out of there. - Me?
-沒錯 -不可能
- Yes. – No.
真的是我
Me?
等下先生
Hey Mr..
讓一下  等一下  就一會兒
Hold on,hold on a second. Just hold on a second.
這附近肯定有什麼東西
It's gotta be something near.
一個破手機
A broken phone.
和克莉絲汀娜喝咖啡
-克莉絲汀娜  -怎麼了
- Christina? - Yeah?
等下
Excuse me.
-跟我一起下車  -我們還沒到站呢
- Hey,hey come with me. - This isn't our stop!
-來吧  去走走  -我們不在這站下
- Now come on,let's take a walk. - We don't get off here.
-我一時性起  -你把我嚇到了
- I don't know,just be spontaneous. - You gonna freaking me up...
雖然聽起來很怪  但我總覺得
I know this gonna sound really weird but I have a
這趟車會發生什麼不幸
really bad feeling about this train
我們該下車  好嗎
and I think that we should get off,ok?
把你的東西帶上
Just get your stuff.
車門即將關閉  請全員上車
All aboard. Doors are closing.
快點  跟我來
Come on,come with me.
-現在呢  -等下  我馬上回來
- So what now? - Wait,one... I'll be right back!
現在可以去喝咖啡了嗎
Ready to get that coffee now?
對不起  再等一會  就一會好嗎
Oh sorry,yeah,ah... Jus… just one more second,ok?
有完沒完
Oh for God's sake.
不舒服嗎
Feel sick?
暈動病  一直都有
It's motion sickness,I get it all the time.
坐過去點 過去點
Excuse me... Excuse me.
-你在跟蹤我嗎  -能用下你的手機嗎
- Are you following me? - Can I borrow your phone?
不行  我沒有手機
No,I don't have one.
-你肯定  -當然
- Sure? - Yeah,I am sure.
你能不能離我遠點  我要報警了
Why you don't leave me alone please? Or I call the police.
用什麼打  你說你沒有手機
With what? I thought you said you didn't have a phone.
要知道  你沒權利...
You know,you have no right...
你幹什麼  把包還我
What are you doing? Give me my bag back.
你瘋了啊
Are you crazy?
他們是誰
Who are they?
-肖恩  -別過來
- Shawn! - Get back!
肖恩  怎麼回事
Shawn,what's going on?
肖恩
Shawn!
快停下  肖恩
Stop,Shawn!
-不是你  -你到底有什麼毛病啊
- It wasn't you. - What the hell is wrong with you?
-你瘋了嗎  -不  不  不
- Are you insane? - No! No,no!
-它在哪裏  -鬆開我
- Where is it? - Get away from me!
-它到底在哪裏  -離我遠點
- Where is it? - Get away from me,please!
肖恩  肖恩  快起來  肖恩
Shawn,Shawn,get up! Shawn!
肖恩  聽我說  快起來
Shawn,listen to me,get up!
-肖恩  -把手給我  從鐵軌那上來
- Shawn. - Give me your hand,get off the track...
-先生  快點  -肖恩  肖恩  肖恩  快起來
- Mr. C'mon. - Shawn,Shawn,Shawn,get up...
考爾特
Colter.
戈德溫  快回答  聽到我說話了嗎
Goodwin? Come in,do you read me?
斯蒂文斯上尉  這是圍城
Captain Stevens,this is Beleaguered Castle,
收了嗎  請回答
do you copy? Please respond.
這在結冰  怎麼回事
It's freezing here,what』s going on.
什麼情況
What's that?
他有麻煩了
He is in trouble.
艙內停止供氧了
I think the oxygen just went out.
戈德溫
Goodwin?
Goodwin!
想辦法聯繫上他
Find a way to get through to him.
怎麼了  發生了什麼事
What is it? What's going on?
三層製冷系統也沒出現異常
It's not the tertiary cooling either.
繼續聯繫他  看他能不能收到信息
Just keep sending strings out,see if he hooks on to something.
我不清楚裏面是個什麼情況
It's hard to say exactly what he's going through.
-長官  -拜託
- Sir? - Please.
我們現在也無能為力
It's not a whole lot we can do from here.
要是情況沒好轉  他還能堅持多久
If nothing changes,how much time does he have?
一會吧
Some...
堅持不了多久
and not long.
莉莉醒來時穿著晚禮服  披著夜禮服斗蓬
Lilly awoke in an evening dress and an opera cloak,
她手上有五張牌
in her hand were 5 playing cards.
分別是紅桃Q  梅花4
They were the queen of space,4 of club.
戈德溫  你聽得見嗎
Goodwin,you out there?
戈德溫  誰是戈德溫
Goodwin,who is Goodwin.
我是斯蒂文斯上尉  聽得見嗎
This is Captain Stevens,do you copy?
斯蒂文斯上尉
Captain Stevens?
機艙內停電了
The capsule lost power.
機艙嗎  上尉  你在機艙裏嗎
The capsule? Is that where you are now,Captain,in a capsule?
你難道不知道嗎  你是誰
You should know,who are you?
我去叫戈德溫上尉  去叫她
Let me get Captain Goodwin,get to it!
是你發明了這玩意兒吧
You invented this thing,right?
-是的  -你是這的主管嗎
-I did. - Are you in command here?
是的  你找到設彈人了嗎  上尉
I am. Were you able to locate the information we need,Captain?
沒能找到 長官
That's a negative Sir. I was unable to find the bomber,
但我救了她  一個火車上的乘客
but I did save her. A passenger on the train.
我讓她安全下了車  一個女人
I got her off safely,a woman.
上尉  如果你試圖拯救車上的任何一人
Captain,it's gonna be counterproductive for you
系統都將對你產生反作用
to try to save anyone on that train.
他們在你的任務範疇之外
They're outside the mission.
但她逃過了這場爆炸  或許其他人也可以
Well,but she survived. And maybe the rest could too.
她僅僅是在源代碼中獲救
She survived,but only inside the Source Code.
他們所有人都難逃一死
None of them will be safe.
什麼是源代碼
What is this Source Code?
這是量子力學寓式微積分
It's quantum mechanics parable calculus.
非常複雜
It's very complicated.
試著跟我解釋一下
Try me!
好吧
Fine.
當你關閉電燈  燈泡仍然有餘輝
When a light bulb's turned off,there is an afterglow,
這叫延遲光圈效應  你見過吧
a lingering halo-like effect. You seen it?
-是的  -很好
- Yes. - Of course.
我們的大腦也一樣
The brain is like that,its electromagnetic
人死後大腦的電磁場仍然處於通電狀態
field remains charged,just briefly even after death.
電路依然通暢
Circuits remain open.
大腦還有一個特性
Now there is another peculiarity about the brain.
它存有一個短期記憶軌跡
It contains a short-term memory track
時長約8分鐘
that's approximately 8 minutes long
就像便利店的安全攝像機一樣
like a convenience store's security camera that
只能在硬盤上記錄
only records the last portion of the day's activity
每一天的最後部分
on its hard drive.
把這兩種現象結合起來
Now combining these two phenomena,circuitry that
人死後腦電圖保持接通
remains viable postmortem and a memory bank
記憶庫前調8分鐘
that goes back 8 minutes
源代碼就能幫助我們利用那重疊部分
Source Code enables us to capitalize on the overlap.
肖恩·芬特雷斯死在了那列火車上
Shawn Fentress died on that train,
在所有乘客中  他是你最好的紐帶
of all the passengers aboard he was your best link.
你們在性格  體型  和突觸圖譜上
You two share the compatibility in terms of gender,
都十分匹配
body size and your synaptic maps.
-那8分鐘後會怎麼樣  -之後  什麼都沒了
- What happens after the 8 minutes? - After? Nothing.
你將不存在於列車上
You cease to exist on the train.
在源代碼中
You cannot exist inside the Source Code,
你無法存在於芬特雷斯記憶的8分鐘外
beyond Fentress' 8 minutes.
源代碼不是時間穿梭
Source Code is not time travel.
而是對時間的再賦值
Rather,Source Code is time reassignment.
它能讓我們進入與現實平行的世界
It gives us access to a parallel reality.
車上人的遇難是個悲劇
Now the deaths on the train were a tragedy
-但是源代碼使我們...  -不對  我確實救了...
- but Source Code empowers us... - No,but I saved
一個人  那個坐在我對面的女人
one person,that girl,that's always
我讓她下了車
sitting across from me. I pulled her off the train.
告訴我她的名字
Give me her name.
克莉絲汀娜  我記不得她姓什麼了
Christina,I don't remember her last name.
-她叫克莉絲汀娜·沃倫   -沒錯
- Her name was Christina Warren. - Yes!
-今年28歲  -就是她
- She was 28. - That's her
生於伊利諾斯州莫林市  死於今早的火車爆炸
born in Moline,Illinois. Died this morning on the train.
不對  我讓她下了車  她沒死
No,no,I pulled her off. She's fine.
-不  她死了  -相信我  她沒死
- No,she isn't. - Believe me,she is.
-相信我  -她看見我被一列快車壓死了
- Believe me. - She saw me get hit by the express train.
-事情沒有任何進展  -不  等等
- This isn't us getting anywhere. - No,no,no,wait,
-等等  -必須把他送回去
- Wait. - We have to send him in.
第二輪爆炸迫在眼前  拉特裏奇博士
A second attack is imminent,Dr. Rutledge.
-什麼二輪爆炸  -列車的爆炸只是一個開始
- What second attack? - The train was just the beginning.
一系列爆炸的開始
A letter of intent.
抱歉  我聽不懂你們在說什麼
I am sorry,what are you telling me here?
我們得到消息
We have information that
芝加哥市中心是下一個目標
Downtown Chicago is the next target.
他們準備在市中心引爆放射性炸彈
And they're planning to detonate a dirty bomb.
你知道如此程度的爆炸
You have any idea how many people would die
會使多少人喪命嗎
if an explosion of that magnitude were to occur in the city?
說話這會兒  我們已經在疏散人群
We're evacuating as we speak.
我們得在炸彈爆炸之前阻止它  懂嗎
We've to stop it before it happens,do you understand?
如果你找到了設彈人  他的第二次爆炸
If you find the bomber,his second attack,
他的真正意圖  就能被阻止
the real attack,we think,can be prevented.
我們沒時間了
We have very little time left.
爆炸一旦發生就無法挽回了
Out here the clocks only move in one direction.
驅動通電
Charge the drivers.
旁邊車廂的二樓
On the upper deck of the next carriage
有一個乘務員室
there is aconductor's compartment.
裏面有一個保險箱
It's a small office containing a strongbox.
箱內有一把上膛的手槍  找到它
Inside is a loaded handgun. Get to it.
必要時你可以使用任何武力
You are authorized to use whatever force necessary.
我採納了你的建議
I took your advice.
很不錯的建議
It was very good advice.
-你還在這兒  -當然
- You're still here. - Of course I am.
你猜怎麼著
Guess what?
你辭了職  報上了NALSAR的課程
You've quit your job and you enrolled in a NALSAR course.
猜得真準
Good guess.
蘇打水罐  咖啡灑了
Soda can. Coffee spill.
聽著  別接這電話
Listen to me... Don't answer this.
他配不上你
You deserve better than that guy.
把一切留給回憶不是更好嗎
Everything looks more beautiful in retrospect,doesn't it?
你怎麼知道...
How did you know there was....
-你對我有多瞭解  -顯然不是很瞭解
- How well do you know me? - Not that well apparently.
那我們有沒有熟到
Do you know me well enough,that if I did something
如果我做了些不合常理
that looked a little strange and was maybe
甚至有點危險的事情
even a little bit dangerous
然後叫你無論如何都要相信我  你會信嗎
and told you to trust me anyway,that you could do that?
不會
No.
真是大實話
Wow,that was honest.
你漂亮  善良
You are beautiful,you're kind,
也有著令人神傷的坦率
and you are painfully honest.
你是誰
Who are you and what did
你對肖恩·芬特雷斯做了什麼
you do with Shawn Fentress?
這是全新的我
It's the new me.
您的車票
Ticket?
我不想傷害你
I don't want to hurt you.
我不會坐回去
No I am not gonna sit in my seat,alright?
他在流血  需要救治
He is bleeding,he needs medical attention.
你想從火車保險箱裏面偷槍
Is it true that you tried
這是真的嗎
to steal a gun out of the train security box?
小心點  女士
Careful ma'm!
-該死  -你瘋了嗎
- Damm it! - What were you thinking?
-我能借用下你手機嗎  -不行
- Can I borrow your phone? - No!
-肖恩  你需要去醫院  -求你了
- You need to go to the hospital,Shawn. - Please!
-求你了  -不行  你需要救治
- Please. - No,you need help.
-我能借用下你手機嗎  -不行
- Can I borrow your phone? - No!
你借我手機做什麼
Why do you want my phone?
要是你只有一分鐘可以活了
What would you do if you only
-你會怎麼做  -我不知道
- had one minute left to live? - I don't know.
我會打電話給我爸
I would call my dad.
仔細聆聽他的聲音
I would hear his voice
然後跟他道歉
and I'd tell him I am sorry.
告訴我一切都會沒事的
Tell me everything is gonna be ok.
一切都會好起來的
Everything is gonna be ok.
是的  槍在保險箱內
Oh yeah,the gun in the strongbox,
真是個好主意  多謝你了
that was a really great idea. Thanks for that.
-有進展嗎  -我能用下電話嗎
- Did you make any progress? - Can I get access to a phone?
我要和我父親通電話
I need to talk to my father.
我待會試下  不騙你
I will try to work on that soon. Yes,I will try.
戈德溫  我表現得怎樣
Goodwin,how I am doing?
我只是知道自己在這的表現如何
I am just trying to measure my performance here.
你有沒有回去過  我比你表現得好嗎
Have you ever gotten back in? Am I doing any better than you did?
我們這是在浪費寶貴的時間
No,we're wasting valuable time here.
沒有  我只參與過源代碼的指揮工作
No,no,I have never been on the other side
我不適合這項任務
of a Source Code mission. I wouldn't be a viable candidate.
為什麼  CAOC-N  那是什麼
Why not? CAOC-N,what is that?
因為適用範圍很窄
Because the specifications are extremely narrow.
什麼適用範圍
What are they?
上尉  你現在本該已經找到設彈人了
Captain,you should have found the suspect by now.
我們賜予了你如此強大的戰略性武器
This tactical advantage,this tremendous tool that we've given you.
別胡思亂想  暴殄天物
Don't squander it thinking.
拿出實際行動來
Do.
請幫我聯繫我父親
Please contact my father for me.
船到橋頭自然直  上尉
This will stop at some point,Captain.
只要你完成了任務
As soon as you finish the mission.
你表現得真的很好  你能做到的
And you're doing really great. This will end.
安置炸彈的人都需要特定的工具
Whoever planted the bomb had to have equipment of some kind.
像手套  開頭頂通風口的螺絲刀
Gloves,a screwdriver to get into the over the head vent,
手電之類的
flashlight,something.
檢查下乘客的提袋  背包  公文包等等
Check bags,backpacks,briefcases,anything.
於是...我採納了你的建議
So... I took your advice.
-很不錯的建議  -老頭
- It was very good advice. - Hey Grandpa!
-你在幹什麼  -我只是...
- What are you doing? - I am just...
在回想些事情
trying to remember something.
-那是什麼  -軍隊的臂章
- What is that? - It's a Military patch.
你參過軍嗎
Were you in the Military?
是我朋友 他在阿富汗服役
A friend of mine was. He was in Afghanistan
然後就消失了  杳無音信
and he disappeared and no one has heard from him since.
你手機可以上網嗎
Do you have the Internet on your phone?
不行  必須要用很長的網線
No,it's just connected to
連接到辦公室才行
the office by a really long piece of string.
-你能幫我找找這個人的嗎  -沒問題
- Do you think,you can see what you can find on this guy? - Sure.
他最近一直在我的腦海中浮現
He's been on my mind a lot lately,
他是考爾特·斯蒂文斯上尉
his name is Captain Colter Stevens,
任職於第17空降部隊
he is in the 17th Airborne.
你欠我一個人情
Ok,you owe me.
以後請你喝咖啡
I'll buy you a cup of coffee...
要想喝我現在就可以給你買一杯
Why don't I get one for you now.
克莉絲汀娜
Christina!
我最近一直做著一些夢
I've been having these dreams lately...
非常真實的夢
Really vivid...
-你也在我夢中  -真的嗎
- and you've been in them. - Really?
不是那種夢
What... oh,no... No that I wouldn't.
我只是
I.. It's just...
我待會兒再打給你  寶貝
I'll call you back in a minute honey.
好的
Yeah.
-臨時抱佛腳嗎  - 是的
- Cramming? - Yeah.
什麼考試
For what?
心理學  今早有個大測驗
Psych. And I got a big test this morning,
那我繼續看了
so I should get back to it.
我能借支筆嗎
Can I borrow a pen?
當然
Yeah,sure.
夥計  這樣可不禮貌
Woooh! Hey,that's not cool man!
-夥計  你的包可真亂  -你幹什麼
- Man... Your bag is a mess. - What you doing man?
跟我的包一樣亂
Never find what I am looking for,
想找東西的時候總找不到
just like my bag. Just like my...
-你還是把包還給人家吧  -一邊弄你的交易去
- How about you let the guy have his bag back? - Finish your deal!
別多管閒事  不然有你好看
Stay out of this tough guy or doesn't end well for you.
你沒權這麼做
You can't do that.
什麼都沒找到  什麼都沒有
What am I doing? What am I doing here?
我去  媽逼的
Jesus. Dick.
C-o-c-n
C-o-c-n.
沃爾特·裏德  部隊醫療中心
打擾了  女士  你好
Excuse me,ma',m. How you doing,
早上好  你在沃爾特·裏德任職嗎
Good morning. You work at Walter Reed?
是的  以前是
Yeah,I used to.
-我是軍人  -你是軍人嗎
- I am in the Military. - You are in the Military?
-是的  -剛才樓下是怎麼回事
- Yeah,yeah I am. - What was going on down there?
我們剛才為這個臂章
Oh you know,we were just having a
發生了一點小爭執
little bit of an argument actually about,about this patch.
軍隊就是這樣訓練你的嗎  襲擊老百姓
Is that what they train you to do? Assault civilians?
女士  拜託看看這些字母中有沒有你熟悉的
Ma'm please. Do any of these letters,they look familiar to you?
你知道N代表什麼嗎
Do you know what the "N" Stands for?
在空軍中  N代表內利斯
It's Air Force and the "N" Stand for Nellis
能借下你手機嗎
Can I borrow your phone?
我可以付錢給你
You know what,actually I can pay for it.
不用借  我可以付你錢
I don't even have to borrow,I can pay you for it.
-我有...100塊  -我不要你的錢
- I have like 100 dollars... - I don't want your money.
-用完還我  -好的  非常感謝
- Just bring it back. - All right,thank you so much.
快點  快點
Come on,come on,come on,come on....
接線員為您服務
Post operator.
-請接拉特裏奇  -請稍等
- Rutledge please. - Please hold.
-請講  -你告訴他
- Say,please? - You tell him
-考爾特·斯蒂文斯上尉打來的  -請稍等
- Captain Colter Stevens is calling. - Hold the line.
車門即將關閉  請全員上車
All aboard. Doors are closing.
馬上接通拉特裏奇博士
Dr Rutledge will be on in a moment.
-我有事要跟你說  -我知道  我找到他了
- I have to tell you something. - I know,I found him.
-你朋友  -我找到他了
- Your friend? - I got him.
-他在阿拉斯加的某空軍基地  -不  他不在
- An Air Force Base. In Las Vegas. - No,he's not.
-肖恩  他死了  -什麼
- He's dead,Shawn. - What?
抱歉  你朋友兩個月前執行任務時殉職了
I am sorry. Your friend was killed in action two months ago.
不  你肯定把名字搞錯了
No,you must have gotten the name wrong.
考爾特·斯蒂文斯
Colter Stevens,
第17空降部隊的直升機飛行員
17th Airborne helicopter pilot,
我查的第一個網站就有
was on the first site I tried.
他父親叫唐納德  對吧
His father's name is Donald,right?
這是上周新聞
This is from last week.
唐納德·斯蒂文斯
Donald Stevens
將與艾倫諾·戈瓦一起
will join host Eleonor Gwah
主持商議他兒子的死
to discuss the death of his son,Army Captain Colter Stevens
陸軍上尉考爾特·斯蒂文斯
who died in Afghanistan
二月死於阿富汗
in February
死後被授予了銀星
and was honored posthumously with the silver star.
新聞中還提到
Also on the broadcast
斯蒂文斯上尉
will be Army Sergent Rorbert Alvarez,
在卡達漢城外的槍戰中
whose life was saved by
救了羅伯特·阿爾瓦雷斯士官一命
Captain Stevens in a firefight just outside of Kandahar.
節哀順變
I'm sorry.
上尉
Captain.
-肖恩  說句話  -上尉
- Shawn... talk to me. - Captain.
斯蒂文斯上尉
Captain Stevens,
我是柯琳·戈德溫上尉
my name is Captain Colleen Goodwin.
這裏是圍城  你沒事了
You're with operation Beleaguered Castle. You are safe.
告訴我你看見了什麼
Now,can you tell me what you see?
-回想一下  -我看見了一張牌
- Just look and think. - I see a card.
很好
That's good.
能聽見嗎  我們受到了猛烈的火箭彈攻擊
Do you copy,we're taking a lot of RPG fire here.
我死了嗎
Am I dead?
一個廣播節目說一架直升機在鄉村墜毀
A radio listing is saying that
我死在裏面了
I died in a helicopter crash in country,
我父親替我接受了勳章
and my father received a medal for me.
你的情況與此任務無關
Your condition is not the issue here
你應該盡力阻止接下來的爆炸
You need to focus on preventing any subsequent attacks.
其他的都無關緊要
Everything else is irrelevant.
新聞說我死了  這無關緊要嗎
News report saying that I am dead is irrelevant?
在火車設彈人
Until the person or persons
被抓到之前  是的
who blew up that train are in custody... yes!
戈德溫
Goodwin.
將心比心  我是死了嗎
One soldier to another. Am I dead?
你大腦的一部分仍在運作
Part of your brain remains activated.
那我身體的其它部分呢
What about the rest of me?
我的手腳仍然可以動
I can see my hands and my feet. They still move.
它們只是表象
They're a manifestation.
是你的主觀想像
They're just your way of making sense of all this.
你是說  這一切都是我的想像嗎
So..What are you saying? Are you saying that I am imagining this?
我想像...自己仍然
I'm imagining that ...I am still alive,
活在這機艙裏嗎
that I am in this capsule?
第四安培數下降
We have fourth amp dropping.
上尉  裏面怎麼了
Captain,what just happened?
能問你個問題嗎
Can I ask you a question?
這個機艙也只是個表象
The capsule is a manifestation as well.
-我在哪兒  -這是機密
- Where am I? - That's classified.
操你媽的
Fuck you!
上尉  我不能體會你現在的心情
Captain,I can not imagine what you must be feeling right now,
但我們必須馬上
but if are to prevent a second attack,
送你回去阻止第二場爆炸
we need to send you back immediately.
上尉  你在源代碼中時
And Captain,you cannot deviate from the mission
不能分心想任務以外的事情  甚至...
while inside the Source Code. Even to investigate your...
不能去深究自己發生了什麼事
Even to investigate what happened to you.
這個終端的程序一致連續  由不得你亂攪和
There is only one continuum on this end and it can't be unsettled.
我剛還真就攪和了  我從車上給你打電話了
Well,you know,I did unsettle it. I called you from the train.
就在爆炸之前
Just before the explosion,
今早7點46分  他們呼叫了你...
so 7:46 this morning they paged you with a call...
你可能在火車上給我打了電話
You may have made that call from the train,
但我在這收不到
but I would never receive it here.
這是不同的世界  上尉
It's a different reality,Captain.
就算電話接通了
If the call even went through it would be
接電話的也是一個完全不同的我
received by a different me entirely.
這你聽起來可能很費解
This may be difficult for you to hear,
但你就是時鐘上的指針
but you are a hand on a clock,understand?
我們給你上了發條  你就開始轉動
We set you,you move forward.
再上一次發條  你又開始轉動
We reset you,you move again.
你的作用就體現在此
And that represents the entirety of your function here.
下次我要給你寄個披薩
You know what,next time,I'll send you a pizza.
我倒要看看  這有沒有用
I see,if that makes an impression.
你無法在源代碼中
You cannot alter the continuum
改變現實的連續性
of this reality from within the Source Code.
你弄的這玩意肯定是違法的
This can't be legal what you are doing.
實際上
In fact,
你大腦的使用權和整個項目
your acquisition by this program as well as the program itself,
都通過了軍事法庭的審核
has been reviewed and sanctioned by a military court.
許多士兵都會認為
You know,many soldiers would
執行這任務比死了要好
find this preferable to death.
因為有機會繼續為國家效力
The opportunity to continue serving their country.
長官
Have you....
你到底經歷過真刀真槍的戰鬥嗎
Have you spent much time in battle,sir?
這無關緊要
That's immaterial.
我的戰友們都會認為
Any soldier I've ever served with
為國效力  死一次就夠了
could say that one death is service enough.
好吧  只要你完成了任務  我就答應你的要求
Fine,you can have that in return for completing this mission.
-什麼要求  -給你你想要的
- Wha... Have what? - I'll give you what you want...
終結你的服役  讓你安息
Terminate your service,let you die.
浪費太多時間了
This is taking too long,
你對他太仁慈  現在起不許休息了
you've been to easy on him. No more rest periods.
我相信  我們會找到跟你受過類似傷
I am certain,we can find other service men with wounds
但卻把執行此任務
similar to yours who'll
視為無上榮耀的士兵
consider being a part of this program an honor.
不不  等等  什麼
No,no,no,no,no. Wait,wait. What?
送他回去  驅動通電
Send him back. Charge the drivers.
斯蒂文斯上尉
And Captain Stevens,
我得提醒你 這可不只是為了你自己
I'd like you to remember that it's not only about you,
更是為了外面兩千萬美國人
but it's also about 2 million real world Americans.
你可能不珍惜你的命
Now you may not value your own life,
但我請你珍惜他們的生命
I do however ask that you value theirs.
建議
Advice....
老頭
Hey Grandpa.....
冷靜下來  你回來了
Calm yourself,you're back.
找到設彈人了嗎
Did you find the bomber?
車上有幾百個人
There... are hundreds of people on that train.
那就一個一個地去檢查
Well,then check them out one by one.
你怎樣對他們都無所謂  反正他們都死了
Doesn't matter what you do to them,they're already dead.
有必要的話  就拿槍殺了他們
Get to that gun and shoot them all if you have to,
但是一定要搞到有用的情報
but get us some usable intel.
不  等等
No! No,wait!
在找到設彈人之前  你必須反覆穿越
We have to keep doing this,until you find the bomber.
擺脫  我一直在努力
Please,I am trying,I am trying
誰是投彈手
Who is the bomber?
我在努力
I am trying.
抱歉  上尉  我知道你很累
I am sorry,Captain. I know you are exhausted
我們也都很沮喪  但我們輸不起
and we are all frustrated,but we can not fail.
你做得到的
You can do this.
-我做不到  -你可以
- I can't,I can't. - Yes,you can.
你天生就是英雄  即使你父親也這樣想
You are a born hero,son. Even your father thinks so.
你最擅長的就是救人於危難之中
Saving people is what you do best.
我們之前有些矛盾  我不想和他修復關係
It was about a stir,too. I didn't wanna regroup back.
我只是開始覺得
I just..... started feeling
他再也不想回家了
like he didn't wanna come home anymore.
-爸  是你嗎  -他還是沒能回來
- Dad? - Somehow,he couldn't come home.
也不願意跟我溝通  或是聽我說話
and he wouldn't talk to me.... wouldn't hear me.
他只說...他不能就這樣
Hardly said he just.... couldn't
離開他的部隊  所以一直在服役
leave his unit out there without him and that was that.
那些戰友  才是他的家人
Those guys.... were his family.
我說了兩件我不該說的事  也許吧
I said two things I shouldn't have. I don't know.
我從未真正瞭解過他
I never fully understood him.
也不敢相信他就這樣死了
And I can't believe he is gone.
送我回去
Send me back in.
拜託別再把我炸飛了
Please don't blow me up again.
撥號  065-012-6758
我知道是你
Hello? I know,it's you.
我會找到你的  給我回頭
I am gonna find you. Turn around?
-你好啊  -我嗎
- Hey there. - Me?
你驚訝個什麼
Why you look so surprised?
坐著別動
Don't.
坐邊上點  快  把包放那兒
Move. Move. Move. The bag over there.
往裏點  把包放對面然後往裏坐
Move over,put the bag over there and move over.
坐過去  把手機給我
Move over. Now hand me your phone.
-這下你玩完了  -什麼
- You're done! You're done. - What?
-你不能再害人了  -什麼  我不明白
- You can't kill anybody anymore. - What? I don't understand.
-你要用手機引爆炸彈  -什麼
- You gonna trigger the bomb with your phone. - What?
我發誓我不知道你在說什麼
I swear I don't know what you're talking about.
聽著  我叫喬治·特洛克山  是個軟體工程師
Listen,my name is George Troxel,I am software engineer,ok?
剛在跟老婆打電話
I was talking to my wife.
再打一次  你再撥一次
Try it again. Your call,dial it again.
那好  我只要按下重播鍵
Ok,I am gonna press redial.
你的電話就會響  然後我就一槍解決你
Your phone is gonna ring and then I gonna shot you.
該死  很抱歉
Shit,I am sorry. Sorry.
你的東西掉了
Hey! You dropped this.
謝謝
Wow,thanks.
車門即將關閉  請全員上車
All aboard. Doors are closing.
該死  不  開門
Shit,no,no!
不
No!
緊急出口
你可以的
Come on!
停車
Stop the train!
伊利諾斯  5CGY847
-德裏克·弗羅斯特  -什麼事
- Derek Frost - Yes?
-瞧瞧這個  -幹啥
- See this? - Yes?
-眼熟嗎  -沒見過
- Recognize it? - No.
-上帝啊  -把錢包給我
- Jesus. - How about you give me your wallet?
好的
Ok.
別摸了  你故意落在火車上了
No,you left it on the train deliberately.
我肯定是...不小心掉的
I... must dropped it.
不  你是故意的
No,you planted it there,
這樣別人就會以為你死了
so everybody would think you were dead.
-我知道是你幹的  -你怎麼什麼都知道
- I know,it's you. - How do you know so much?
這他媽是什麼
Hell is that thing?
給我悠著點
Wow,wow,wow. Wow,wow. Slow down,slow down.
-你想看看嗎  -挺愛國的嘛
- Do you wanna see it? - Very patriotic-
動作慢點
Slowly,slowly!
好了好了  退後  退後
All right,all right. Back up,back up! Back up!
不是人人都做得出來的
Not many people could build that.
好吧  你下一個目標是什麼
Alright,where is your next target?
肖恩
Shawn?
我的天啊
Oh my god.
肖恩·芬特雷斯
Shawn Fentress.
老師  教歷史的
Teacher. History.
我不認識你
I don't know you.
我好像把你女朋友殺了
I think I killed your girlfriend.
為什麼
Why?
你把我的計劃搞亂了
Oh,you messed up my timing.
為什麼
Why!?
你是說為什麼做這個
Oh,you mean why this.
因為這世界簡直是地獄
Because the world is hell.
但我們可以從廢墟中創造一個新世界
But we have a chance to start over in the rubble
前提是  先把它夷為平地
but first there has to be rubble
你是老師  你會明白的
You are teacher. You..... will understand.
克莉絲汀娜  挺住
Christina... Stay with me!
挺住
Stay with me!
一切都會好起來的
Everything is gonna be ok.
一切還沒有結束
This isn't the end.
那兒檢查一遍  我查這邊
Check through there I'll go check this way.
這裏是圍城
This is Beleaguered Castle.
上尉  這裏是圍城  請確認通信
Captain,this is Beleaguered Castle. Acknowledge transmission.
斯蒂文斯上尉  這裏是圍城
Captain Stevens,this is Beleaguered Castle,
請確認通信
acknowledge transmission.
我找到設彈人了  我知道他名字了
I have your bomber,I have his name.
你有他名字了嗎
You have the bomber's name?
德裏克·弗羅斯特
Derek Frost.
他在格倫布魯克站停車場
He got into a rented white
鑽進了一輛租來的白色貨車
van in the Glenbrook Station parking lot.
伊利諾斯牌照  5CGY847
Illinois plate,5CGY847
好  我們行動
All right,let's move.
對了  戈德溫  等等
And Goodwin..... and Goodwin,
車裏還有一個放射性裝置
there is a radioactive device in the van
某種炸彈
some kind of bomb.
- 謝謝  上尉  -不謝  女士
- Thank you,Captain. - Yes,Ma'm
謝謝  上尉
Thank you,Captain.
-你的任務完成了  -之前說好的呢
- You now off the clock. - About our deal?
我希望你能站在這個項目的立場上
I had hoped that you might reconsider that
重新考慮一下
for the sake of the program.
考慮過了  我現在想要點別的
I have,I want something else now.
好啊
Good.
我還是想死  但我想
I.... I still wanna die,but I wanna
先回去  救下車上人的性命
go back in and I wanna save all those people on that train first.
那不會有用的
It doesn't work that way,
-沒用的  -我知道  我都知道
- It can't. - No,I know,I know,I know....
我不指望你相信我  先生
I am not really asking to believe me,sir.
我只是...向您請求這樣一個機會
I am just..I am asking to have the decency to let me try.
CPD2這裏是AS11
CPD2 this is AS11
貨車已駛近沼澤角  正駛向採石場  完畢
Van is approaching fens cape to the quarry,over.
收到  AS11  我們正前往採石場
Roger that,AS11. We're on the vehicle,that into the quarry road.
我們將在半路實施攔截  完畢
We'll stop him about half way down,over.
AU-SWAT2  這是CPD2
AU-SWAT2,this is CPD2,
封鎖這條路的東面出口  完畢
block the east end of the road,over.
AU-Swat2  收到
AU-Swat2,roger that.
我們現在切換到
We are going to switch now
來自芝加哥的現場報道
to a live feed from our Chicago affiliate.
特種部隊已逼近白色貨車
The swat team is approaching the white van.
今天上午  警方鎖定了一名伊利諾斯男子
An Illinois man has been sorted through this morning...
車門...車門開了
The door is op... the door is open and
嫌疑犯被制伏  目前看來他已投降
the man is on the ground. It appears he has surrendered.
今天早些時候  警察在他後院的棚屋裏
Earlier today the police discovered a.....
-祝賀你  上尉  -發現了一個實驗室
- Congratulations,Captain. - .....lab in the backyard shack..
近幾個月  弗羅斯特開始在
In recent months Frost started
個人網站上發表反政府言論
posting anti-government statements on his website.
好的  這是對整個項目的認可
Yes Sir,it's a real validation of the program
充分展示了源代碼的革命性意義
a clear window into just how revolutionary Source Code can be.
我們終於掌握了反恐的致命武器
We finally have a powerful weapon now in the war on terror.
祝賀你  上尉  幹得漂亮
Congratulations Captain,job well done.
他不準備把我再送回去了吧  戈德溫
He is not gonna send me back in,is he,Goodwin?
我還在等回復
I am still waiting an answer.
上尉  你結婚了嗎
Are you married,Captain?
傑夫  休息一下吧  你該好好慶祝慶祝
Jeff,why don't you go take a break? You deserve to celebrate.
當然
Sure.
-要給你帶點什麼嗎  -不  不用了
- Can I get you something? - No,I am fine.
為什麼問這個  想約我嗎
Why,you asking me on a date?
不好意思  無意冒犯
Sorry,poor taste.
你結婚了嗎
Are you married?
沒有
No.
我離了
I am divorced.
你覺得有沒有另一個自己
You think there is an alternate version of you?
一個做出不同選擇的戈德溫
A Goodwin who made different choices?
什麼意思
What do you mean?
比如說  你沒有結婚
like uh,you didn't get married or
也沒離婚  或者剛和別人結了婚
you didn't get divorced,or just married someone else
選擇了人生中不同的岔路
a woman who has took a different fork in the road?
不  我不覺得  上尉
No,I don't,Captain.
你所經歷的只是幻影
What you experienced was a shadow,
是一個遇害者腦中的殘像
it was an afterimage of a victim on a train.
這裏才是真實世界
This is real life,here.
跟掛掉的飛行員通話也叫真實嗎
The one where you talking to a dead helicopter pilot?
這個程序的初衷不是為了改變過去
The program wasn't designed to alter the past,
而是左右未來  這你已經做到了這點
it was designed to affect the future. And you have done that.
我搞砸了點事情  上尉
I missed something,Captain.
那列車不該爆炸
That train shouldn't have blown up.
肯定還有另一個引爆器
There must have been a second detonator.
備用的  我沒發現
Something I couldn't see. A fail-safe.
這是電腦程序  上尉
It's a computer program,Captain.
車上的姑娘  還有其他人  都已經死了
The girl on the train,all the others,they're lost.
我很抱歉
I am sorry about that.
我知道的
I get it. I get it.
量子物理  寓式積分
I know,quantum physics,parable calculus.
但你錯了  戈德溫  大錯特錯
You're wrong,Goodwin. You're just plain wrong.
上尉  克莉絲汀娜已經死了
Captain,Christina is dead.
她有機會活下去的
She doesn't have to be,Ma'm.
我問問拉特裏奇
I'll ask Rutledge.
我求求你
I'm asking you.
求你...把我...送...
I'm asking you..... Just..... send me.....
送我回去  終止我的生命
只要八分鐘而已  戈德溫
上尉
Captain.
決定權在你
It's your choice.
這段源代碼結束時我會關閉生命維持系統
At the end of this Source Code I'll terminate your life support.
你再也不會回來了
There willl be no coming back.
我一定能拯救她  戈德溫
I am gonna save her,Goodwin!
很榮幸為你效勞  上尉
It was an honor,Captain.
謝謝你的表現
And I thank you for your service.
祝你好運
Good luck.
我採納了你的建議
I took your advice.
你要去印度當老師了
You're gonna move to India and become a Guru.
當心  女士
Careful,ma'm.
沒錯  我要在深山裏找尋自我
Yeah,I am gonna go find myself in the mountains.
走之前  你也許可以跟我喝杯咖啡
Well maybe you have a cup of coffee with me before you go.
好啊  我很想做那個前青春期測試
Yeah,I like to do that pre-teen test.
好的
Good.
要不今天做吧
Let's do it today.
把班翹掉  布萊恩可以找別的助手
Let's just skip work. Bryan can find someone else to assist him.
-你知道嗎  -知道什麼
- You know what? - What?
我感覺很棒
I feel really good.
為什麼
Why?
因為就你這一杯咖啡
Cause I have been waiting for weeks
我都等好幾個星期了
for you to ask me for a coffee.
您的票
Ticket.
好的
Ok.
等我幾分鐘好嗎  我馬上回來
Just give me a couple of minutes ok? And I'll be right back.
我得去...拯救世界
Gotta go... save the world.
我就知道他是個悶騷子
I knew he was a keeper.
天氣真不錯
Beautiful day.
-您的票  -不好意思  對不起
- Ticket. - Oh,I am sorry. Sorry.
你相信國防部嗎
You trust the DOD?
他們掌管財政大權
They got the finances.
是啊  沒錯  如果我們拿到資金
Yeah,well sure. Look,if we get the funding.
我向你保證  我們在年底前
I guarantee you... we can have at least....
至少會有八個源代碼計劃在正常運轉
8 Source Code projects up and running by the end of the year.
-真會有那麼多嗎  -說不定會更多
- Really that many? - Maybe more.
-你真是大英雄  拉特裏奇博士  -謝謝
- You're real hero,Dr. Rutledge. - Oh,thank you.
我們今天確實救了不少人
We did save lives today.
是啊  項目大獲全勝
Yes,a true victory for the program.
-是我們共同的勝利  -以後再聊
- A great victory for us all. - We'll talk soon.
激動人心的時刻到了
So...... exciting times.
啟動SC-1記憶移除程序
Let's initialize the memory wipe on SC-1
開始處理數據
and start crunching the data.
先生
...Sir...
我們不是跟斯蒂文斯上尉說好了
We,we.... we told Captain Stevens,
讓他安息的嗎
that we were gonna let him die.
讓他死  他剛剛救下了無數條生命
Let him die? He just saved millions of lives today.
有了他  以後能避免多少災難
How many other disasters might he avert down the line?
而且據我們所知  他可能
For all we know,he may be
是能讓這套系統運行的唯一人選
the only candidate with which the system works.
所以  清除他的記憶  初始化源代碼
So,let's clear his memory and reinitialize Source Code.
好嗎
Shall we?
遵命
Yes,sir.
不好意思  我...
Sorry,I just....
德裏克  你不在這站下呀
Hey Derek,this isn't your stop.
先生  你把這個掉了
Hey Mr. You dropped this.
過來  到後面來
Come on,back here.
德裏克
Derek.
都結束了
It's over.
明白嗎
Do you understand?
我叫德裏克·弗羅斯特
Hey,my name is Derek Frost.
我在一輛白色貨車中安置了一個核裝置
I planted a nuclear device in a white van,
車停在格倫布魯克站的CCR停車場
parked in a Glenbrook Station CCR parking lot
現在我被銬在944 CCR列車的扶手上
right now I am handcuffed to a pole
列車正駛往芝加哥聯合站
on the 944 CCR train,headed to Chicago Union Station.
我是個變態的可憐蟲
I am a sick and pathetic human being.
我渴望一段漫長的監獄之旅
And I need to be locked away for a very long time.
好了
Ok.
德裏克  今天你是夷不平這個世界了
Derek,there's no more burying the world in rubble today.
不介意我借用一下吧
You mind if I borrow this?
上尉  我們哥幾個要去慶祝一下
Captain,some of the guys and I are gonna go celebrate.
他們讓我啟動記憶清除程序  上尉
And.... they want me to initiate the memory wipe,Captain.
你好  上尉
Hello,Captain.
-你好  -是唐納德·斯蒂文斯嗎
- Hello? - Donald Stevens?
是我
Yes.
-我叫肖恩·斯蒂文斯  -你是誰
- My name is Shawn Fentress. - Who?
我和您兒子考爾特一起服役
I served with your son,Colter.
天哪
Oh boy...
很抱歉這麼久才打電話給你
It's a..... I am sorry it has taken me so long to.... call you.
有時候自己需要一些時間
Sometimes it just takes a while
才能找到最想說的話
to figure out what you wanna say,you know.
別太勉強自己
Ah,don't be too hard on yourself...
打這個電話並不容易
It's not an easy call to make.
先生  您過得還好嗎
How are you doing,Sir?
運回來的只有些骨灰
All that came back was some ash.
很難相信那就是他
It's hard to believe that it was him.
你有多瞭解他
How well did you know him?
他犧牲的時候我在場  他說...
I was there when he died,Sir. He said...
你們的最後一次談話  言辭很激烈...
that the last time that you guys talked,ehm... was tough ....and
他想說聲對不起
he wanted to say that he was sorry.
我只想讓他平安回來
I just wanted him back.
我很愛他
I loved him so much.
-真希望能親口告訴他  -他知道的
- I wish I could have told him that. - He knows it.
保重  斯蒂文斯先生
Take care,Mr. Stevens.
-你沒事吧  -沒事
- You ok? - Yeah.
-拯救世界了  -差不多吧
- Saved the world? - Sorta.
剛說到哪兒了
So,where were we?
去喝咖啡
Getting some coffee.
這是拉特裏奇博士
Dr. Rutledge?
什麼
What?
該死
Shit!
這有什麼難的  我是經商的好嗎
What is too hard about it? I run a business,ok?
要麼按時完成工作  要麼捲鋪蓋滾蛋
Everything moves on time or people get fired.
現實世界就是這麼殘酷
That's how it works in the real world.
-十分鐘  -老兄
- 10 Minutes. - Hey buddy.
別為些瑣事汗流浹背  小心汗水逆流成河
Don't sweat the small stuff,you'll drown.
多謝大師指點迷津
Oh thank you for the moment of Zen,
但我又沒跟你說話
but nobody was talking to you.
你算什麼  大喇叭廣播嗎
What do you sound,self help cds today?
管好自己的事得了
Why don't you just mind your own business?
保安  帶一隊人馬過來  速度
Security? Get me a detachment of MPs here. This instant!
為什麼你老愛挖苦人呢  馬克思
Why are you always so bitter,Max?
朋友  這世界就是如此殘酷
It's a bitter world we living my friend.
你想讓我怎麼辦
What you want from me?
沒必要這樣的
It doesn't have to be.
我賭一百塊
I will bet you 100 dollars,
賭你不能把車裏所有人逗笑
that you can't make all the people on this train laugh.
好了
Oh right...
這總共有...126塊
Actually,126 bucks.
你就這麼玩兒我嗎
Is that your way of making fun of me?
不  為了讓今天多點歡樂
No,it is to have a better day...
不  我接受  手到擒來
No,no. It's good. Easiest money ever.
打擾一下  朋友們  我的一個乘客朋友
Hey,I... excuse me,people. One of our fellow passengers
給了我點錢
has decided to offer me some money....
你今天怎麼了
What has just gotten into you today?
像是變了個人
You're like a different person.
-這是全新的我  -我喜歡
- It's the new me. - I like it.
女人們總把我的姓搞錯
Women always mess up my last name.
有天晚上我跟一姑娘在一起
I was with a girl the other night and
她總是叫我"滾開"
she kept calling me "Getoff".
譯注: 滾開在英語中與此人姓氏諧音
她說  滾開  滾開  我說  不  我叫丹諾夫
She goes "Get off,get off" "I am "No,Denoff,
她說  不是  你又胖又重  快滾開
Denoff",she: "No,you are fat and you are heavy,get off!"
好了嗎  還要二十秒
Good? 20 seconds.
給你十秒
Make it 10.
戈德溫
Goodwin.
看看這一切
Look at all this.
什麼
What?
所有這些生命
All this life.
戈德溫  快把安全門打開
Goodwin,open the SC door!
為什麼你總不停看表
Why you keep looking at your watch?
克莉絲汀娜  如果你只有一分鐘不到的生命
Christina,what would you do....
你會怎麼做
if you knew you had less than a minute to live?
我會讓每秒都過得有意義
I'd make those seconds count.
-我會再吻你一次  -你吻過嗎
- I'd kiss you again. - Again?
戈德溫  把這該死的門打開
Goodwin,open this god damn door!
他已經付出夠多了  博士
He has done enough,Dr.
一切都會好起來的
Everything is gonna be ok.
今天是週一  芝加哥的天氣很好
It is a beautiful Monday in Chicago today.
最低溫度可能會達到60華氏度
Temperature is expected to reach the lower 60.
目前湖上溫度為55華氏度
Right now 55 at the Lake....
-他賭贏了  -是啊
- What,he earned that money. - Yea,he did.
他很搞笑的
He is funny.
搞的我現在沒錢了
Speaking of which... I have no cash.
過來  我想讓你看點東西
Come here,I wanna show you something.
天氣真好啊
It's such a beautiful day,isn't it
沒錯  棒極了
Yeah,it is a really perfect day.
-你相信命運嗎  -不太信
- Do you believe in fate? - Not really.
只能撞些狗屎運  過來
I'm more of a dumb luck kind of gal. Come here.
你今天想幹什麼
So,what do you wanna do today?
我們應該在這多待一會兒
I think we should stay here for a while.
我們命中注定要來這個地方  不是嗎
This feels like exactly where we're supposed to be,doesn't it?
-早上好  傑夫  -早上好  上尉
- Good Morning,Jeff. - Good Morning,Captain.
莉莉醒來時穿著晚禮服  披著夜禮服斗蓬
Lilly awoke in an evening dress and an opera cloak.
她手中拿著五張牌
In her hand were 5 playing cards.
今天某個時候
At some point today,
你會得知在芝加哥附近的列車上
you re gonna hear about
有一個作案未遂的恐怖襲擊犯
a failed terrorist attack on a commuter train near Chicago.
是我們阻止了炸彈爆炸
You and I kept that bomb from going off.
有人想在芝加哥城外的CCR列車上引發爆炸
An attempted bombing on a CCR train outside Chicago
危險已被解除  在列車上發現了嫌疑犯
but it was foiled. And the suspect was found on board....
名叫德裏克·弗羅斯特
Named Derek Frost.
戈德溫  有什麼事嗎
Goodwin,anything I can help you with?
沒什麼  我一會兒再來
No,that's fine,I'll come back later.
瞪大你的眼睛
Well,keep an eye out.
這幾天  總會有危機浮出水面
One of these days,the right crisis is going to rear its head
那時候就該源代碼大展身手了
and Source Code is going to have its moment in the sun.
遵命  長官
Yes,Sir.
如果你現在正在讀這封郵件
If you re reading this email,
那說明源代碼比你和拉特裏奇博士
then Source Code works even better than
想的要強大
you and Dr. Rutledge imagined.
你們以為自己在重現過去的8分鐘
You thought you were creating 8 minutes of a past event,
但事實並非如此
but you're not.
你們創造了一個新世界
You've created a whole new world.
戈德溫  如果我沒弄錯的話
Goodwin,if I am right...
在源代碼設備的某處
Somewhere at the Source Code facility,
有一名在等待執行任務的考爾特·斯蒂文斯上尉
you have a Captain Colter Stevens,waiting to send on a mission.
請一定答應我  你會向他伸出援手
Promise me you'll help him.
那時  也請幫我一個忙
And when you do,do me a favor.
記得告訴他  一切都會好起來的
Tell him,everything is gonna be ok.